<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Affective Analyses | USTC-AC</title>
    <link>https://ustc-ac.github.io/tag/affective-analyses/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ustc-ac.github.io/tag/affective-analyses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Affective Analyses</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ustc-ac.github.io/media/icon_huc3da470f1a231b6fd15916059be12d5d_66382_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Affective Analyses</title>
      <link>https://ustc-ac.github.io/tag/affective-analyses/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multimodal Deep Regression Bayesian Network for Affective Video Content Analyses</title>
      <link>https://ustc-ac.github.io/publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ustc-ac.github.io/publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The inherent dependencies between visual elements and aural elements are crucial for affective video content analyses, yet have not been successfully exploited. Therefore, we propose a multimodal deep regression Bayesian network (MMDRBN) to capture the dependencies between visual elements and aural elements for affective video content analyses. The regression Bayesian network (RBN) is a directed graphical model consisting of one latent layer and one visible layer. Due to the explaining away effect in Bayesian networks (BN), RBN is able to capture both the dependencies among the latent variables given the observation and the dependencies among visible variables. We propose a fast learning algorithm to learn the RBN. For the MMDRBN, first, we learn several RBNs layer-wisely from visual modality and audio modality respectively. Then we stack these RBNs and obtain two deep networks. After that, a joint representation is extracted from the top layers of the two deep networks, and thus captures the high order dependencies between visual modality and audio modality. In order to predict the valence or arousal score of video contents, we initialize a feed-forward inference network from the MMDRBN whose inference is intractable by minimizing the KullbackCLeibler (KL)divergence between the two networks. The back propagation algorithm is adopted for finetuning the inference network. Experimental results on the LIRIS-ACCEDE database demonstrate that the proposed MMDRBN successfully captures the dependencies between visual and audio elements, and thus achieves better performance compared with state-of-the-art work.














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-fig-the-framework-of-our-proposed-method-first-we-train-a-multimodal-generative-network-it-consists-of-two-stacked-rbns-that-are-created-for-visual-and-audio-modalities-respectively&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Fig. The framework of our proposed method. First, we train a multimodal generative network. It consists of two stacked RBNs that are created for visual and audio modalities respectively.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/featured_hu0ff0903a4051f103a27ffc3b5d24d0b2_144232_33de511fe787d72c7424d929317c4505.jpg 400w,
               /publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/featured_hu0ff0903a4051f103a27ffc3b5d24d0b2_144232_70c0a87a200289b1d89f4c6a966a6481.jpg 760w,
               /publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/featured_hu0ff0903a4051f103a27ffc3b5d24d0b2_144232_1200x1200_fit_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://ustc-ac.github.io/publication/dblp-conficcv-gan-whj-17/featured_hu0ff0903a4051f103a27ffc3b5d24d0b2_144232_33de511fe787d72c7424d929317c4505.jpg&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;411&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Fig. The framework of our proposed method. First, we train a multimodal generative network. It consists of two stacked RBNs that are created for visual and audio modalities respectively.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Domain Knowledge for Affective Video Content Analyses</title>
      <link>https://ustc-ac.github.io/publication/dblp-confmm-chen-wwc-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ustc-ac.github.io/publication/dblp-confmm-chen-wwc-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The well-established film grammar is often used to change visual and audio elements of videos to invoke audiences’ emotional experience. Such film grammar, referred to as domain knowledge, is crucial for affective video content analyses, but has not been thoroughly explored yet. In this paper, we propose a novel method to analyze video affective content through exploring domain knowledge. Specifically, take visual elements as an example, we first infer probabilistic dependencies between visual elements and emotions from the summarized film grammar. Then, we transfer the domain knowledge as constraints, and formulate affective video content analyses as a constrained optimization problem. Experiments on the LIRIS-ACCEDE database and the DEAP database demonstrate that the proposed affective content analyses method can successfully leverage well-established film grammar for better emotion classification from video content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
